原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  冰蓝    洗七里
翻译:  人生淫家赛太公
校对:  赛太公与YY猫一起攻克难关
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第九季 第七集
感恩节晚餐
大家都有酒了吗  我要开始感恩节祝酒了
Does everyone have a glass? I'm just giving my Thanksgiving toast.
拜托老爸  你不觉得这样很怪吗
Oh, come on, Dad. Isn't it weird that
每年都要选一个不知为何
every year you single out one person
反正就是让你觉得格外骄傲的人
who somehow made you extra proud this year?
这让我们其他人觉得...
It makes the rest of us feel like we --
是你  克莱尔
It's you, Claire.
真棒  我就知道
Yeah! I knew it!
还有你  菲尔  米奇尔
And you, Phil, and you, Mitchell.
实际上是你们所有人
Actually, it's all of you.
我知道我在家庭中引发竞争
I know I get a hard time
你们都对我都颇有微词
for stirring up competition in the family,
但瞧瞧结果
but look at the results.
菲尔新开了家魔术用品店
Phil scoring with his new magic shop.
小卡带的球队赢得了重要比赛
Cam winning the big game.
克莱尔赢了跑步比赛
Claire winning the race.
而米奇尔吓跑了那个小偷
And Mitchell scaring away that burglar.
你也是赢家  杰
And you are a winner, too, Jay.
他想跟乔共度更多时光
He wanted to spend more time with Joe,
所以他每天
so he's dropping him off
都送他上学  接他放学
and picking him up from school every day.
爸爸  她怎么了
Dad, what is wrong with her?
我挑战她
I challenged her to get
一周内走十万步
to 100,000 steps in a week.
-那很容易  -真容易
- That's easy. - That's so easy.
不算购物
Without shopping.
-我明白挑战难处了  -不
- I get -- I get the challenge. - No.
她还剩1000步就获得荣誉了
She's 1,000 steps from glory.
跟你们一样
Like the rest of you,
她的动力来源于我吝啬赞美
she was motivated by my stingy praise.
我环顾四周  看到的全是赢家
As I look around the room, I see nothing but winners,
我感到十分骄傲
and I couldn't be prouder.
敬我们
To us!
这里的每个人都是赢家
Everyone here is a winner.
那天早些时候
你知道这场重要比赛让我很紧张
You knew I was nervous about the big game,
所以你拿出了我的  好吧
so you set out my -- Okay.
糖屑是给英雄准备的
Sprinkles are for heroes.
给  二爸
Here, Daddy.
谢谢你保护我们
Thank you for protecting us.
我们都为米奇尔那天做的事感到骄傲
We're all so proud of Mitchell about what happened the other day.
我的想法是我们可以...
What I was thinking was, we could...
天啊
Oh, my gosh!
有人闯入了吗
Was there a break-in?
对啊对啊  简直要疯了
Yeah, yeah. It was -- It was crazy.
我当时就冲他吼叫
I just started yelling at him,
我好像就把他吓跑了  所以...
and I guess I scared him away, so...
天啊  亲爱的  你没事吧
Oh, my gosh, sweetie. Are you okay?
是的  我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
-你真勇敢  -宝贝
- You're so brave. - Oh, honey.
万分骄傲
So proud.
如果小偷回来了  而勇敢二爸不在的话
If the robber comes back when Brave Daddy isn't here,
-我们可以用这个  -不不
- we can use these. - Okay, no, no, no, no.
那是我在学校没收的
I had to confiscate those at school.
这很危险
They're very dangerous,
而且你最好还是避开这种亚洲人爱玩的玩意
and, plus, you should avoid the cliche.
没收违禁品是我在学校新工作的一部分
Confiscating contraband is part of my new job at school.
我最近升职为
I was recently promoted to
代理[演戏]副校长了
acting vice principal.
这跟演戏毫无关系
Which has nothing to do with acting.
他们非常明确地跟我说了
That was made very clear to me.
你看起来有些紧张
Hey. Hey. Y-You seem a little nervous.
你是在担心这场重要比赛吗
Are you -- Are you worried about the big game?
是啊  我有些紧张
Yeah. I'm a little nervous.
响尾蛇队过去六年里都打败了我们
The Rattlesnakes have beat us the last six years,
而我们不能输
and we cannot lose.
你这么紧张是因为他们的教练是女人吗
Is any of this because their coach is a woman?
我们不该支持她吗  因为
I mean, shouldn't we be rooting for her, because --
因为她是另一个执教橄榄球的直女吗
Oh, what, because she's another straight person coaching football?
-祝你好运  -谢谢你  亲爱的
- Well, good luck. - Thank you, sweetie.
我无法保证我让你感受到的骄傲
You know, I can't promise that I'll make you as proud as your daddy
和打跑了小偷的二爸一样多  但我会努力
who fought off a burglar, but I will try.
有传言说后援俱乐部
You know, there's murmurs that the booster club
要把给我们的一些经费转给科学项目
is gonna divert some of our money to the science program.
因为这样就能让肯尼迪们变酷
Because that's what made the Kennedys cool, you know --
在草坪上玩科学什么的
playing science on the lawn.
第一个想出怎么把号码布一次贴到位的人
Ow! The first person who figures out how to stick these numbers
肯定能发大财
right on is gonna be rich.
你可以在穿上背心之前先贴好啊
You could just pin it to your shirt before you put it on.
你跟别人分享过这个点子吗
Have you shared this idea with anyone else?
艾丽克斯小时候  我会把她放进慢跑婴儿车里
When Alex was a baby, I used to throw her in a jogging stroller,
她是我的跑步伙伴
and she was my running buddy.
这周她得知我要跑一万米时
This week, when she found out I was doing a 10K,
就坚持要来
she insisted on coming.
无聊死了
Snore.
我把我妈当做我的白痴心理学论文的对象
I'm using my mom as a subject for my stupid psych paper
因为我开始太晚了  没法领走猴子了
because I started too late to sign out a monkey.
论文是关于积极与消极强化的
It's about positive versus negative reinforcement.
比赛前半程我会喊  "你能做到的  妈"
First half of the race -- "You can do it, Mom!"
后半程则是  "算了吧  女人"
Second half -- "It's not your day, lady!"
幸好  做完实验后
Thankfully, after it's done,
给猴子买的香蕉可以给她吃
I'll still be able to give out the banana I bought.
多谢你照顾乔
Thank you so much for taking care of Joe.
我还得去店里买点晚餐食材
I still have to get some things from the store for dinner.
没问题
It's no problem.
我有很多知识可以传授
I got a lot of knowledge to pass on.
你有在持续练习打嗝吗
You been practicing your burping drills?
是的
Yes!
-好些了  -好  闲聊完了
- Better. - Okay, enough chitchat.
给我促销的VIP票
Give me the V.I.P. Pass for the sale.
大家都听说过H.布朗夫曼服装的
Everybody's heard of the H. Bronfman Clothiers
黑五促销  那时候大伙儿
Black Friday sale where the hoi polloi
像动物一样疯狂争抢晚礼服
fight over tuxedos like animals.
但是在感恩节
But on Thanksgiving Day,
极少数人会受邀当第一批进场的买家
a select few are invited to get first crack.
如果我能把要的都买齐
If I get everything I want,
我的燕尾服就会在小姑娘房里脱到只剩两成
that tux will be 80% off in Tammy Bosworth's dorm room.
黑金卡
Black gold.
这是俱乐部成员当做小费给我的
I got it as a tip from some club members
他让我弄来几瓶灰雁伏特加
who had me "deal" with some geese.
你休想玷污这次体验
You will not taint this experience.
克莱尔  你为什么贴着号码布
Claire, why do you have that number?
你参加选美比赛了吗
Are you in a pageant?
她要跑一万米  她的表现一定会很棒
She's running a 10K. And she is going to do great.
我就知道你会让我们感到骄傲
I know that you're gonna make us oh-so proud!
显然这本该是群抱
Obviously, this was meant to be a group hug,
而我的邀请函在邮寄时遗失了
and my invitation got lost in the mail. Mm.
菲尔  你为了变魔术
Phil... that crazy phone booth
订的那个疯狂电话亭
that you ordered for your magic trick --
已经在我家了
It's already at my house.
提前两天到了吗
It's here two days early?!
我今天就能拍摄教程
I can shoot my how-to video today!
海莉  好戏上演了
Haley! Showtime!
毫无疑问  二战中
It goes without saying that the greatest trick
最伟大的魔术就是诺曼底电话亭
to come out of World War II is the Normandy Phone Booth.
多年来  它的名声时起时落
Over the years, its reputation has ebbed and flowed.
众所周知  在1969年的
It was famously booed
纳拉干塞特魔术节上它遭到了大家的喝倒彩
at the 1969 Narragansett Magic Festival.
当然  那时候
Of course, this is a time
大部分人都在抗议魔术
when most people are into protest magic.
所以很自然  他们会对经典魔术嗤之以鼻
So naturally, they would thumb their nose at a classic trick
那就是一个英勇的士兵冲进电话亭
where a heroic soldier dashes into a phone booth
打了拯救世界的电话
to make a world-saving call
而电话亭慢慢灌满了水
while it slowly fills with water!
这多赞啊  嬉皮士们
Come on, hippies!
天啊
God!
小家伙  你出去玩吧
All right, buddy. Run outside and play real quick.
我要去楼上忙些事
I'm gonna take care of something upstairs.
我得更新我在
I had to update my profile pic
一款新社交媒体软件"内缝线"上的用户照片
on this new social-media app called Inseam.
这软件超酷的  基本还没人知道
It's super cool. No one knows about it.
有些老家伙用它分享自制成衣
Some old guys were using it for home tailoring,
但之后两个布鲁克林DJ
but then two Brooklyn deejays
开始在上面分享一些视频  然后就火了
started sharing a couple of videos on it, and it blew up.
太严肃了
Not approachable.
太亲和了
Too approachable.
完美
There's my guy.
怎么了
What's up?
伙计  我刚准备离开
Dude, I was just about to leave,
结果在内缝线上看见了你的新照片
and I saw your new pic popped up on Inseam.
你也用内缝线吗
You're on Inseam?
是的  我已经用了一周了
Yes, I've been on it for a week.
你看看照片  乔在你身后的树上
Okay, look at your picture. Joe is in a tree behind you.
天啊  他就在那里
Oh, my God, he's right there!
等等  乔
Hang on, Joe!
喂
Hello?
乔怎么了
What's going on with Joe?
你也用内缝线吗
You're on Inseam?
当然了
Of course I'm on Inseam.
我儿子挂在树上了吗
Is my son hanging from a tree?
真棒  你信了
Oh, that's great! You fell for it.
我的改图技术越来越出神入化啊
I'm, uh -- I'm getting pretty good at Photoshop.
那是假照片吗
That's a fake picture?
是啊  我有许多张乔做危险事情的照片
Yeah, I got a bunch of Joe doing dangerous stuff.
那你晚点给我看看  好吗
You're gonna have to show me this later, okay?
没问题
Will do.
都怪你
Well, thanks to you,
我现在满身大汗  都没办法
now I'm all sweaty, and it's gonna be impossible
鉴定丝绸衬衫了
to judge the silk shirts.
应该宽松飘逸  而不是黏身上
They're supposed to blouse, not cling.
能让我看看这张卡吗
Hey, can I see that card for a second?
-你干什么  -等你把乔的头P到鳄鱼嘴里
- What are you doing? - I'll put this card back in your hand
我才会把这张卡交还给你
when you Photoshop that kid's head in an alligator's mouth.
上游河谷在二码线上
Upper Valley on the 2-yard line
比赛时间还剩十秒
with 10 seconds to go.
一个触地得分将会获胜
A touchdown will win the game.
暂停  暂停
Okay, timeout! Timeout!
加油  海豚队
Let's go, Dolphins!
教练  我们怎么防守
Coach, what is our defense?
好吧  按理说应该用奔跑达阵
Okay, you know what? It's a running situation,
但他们用传球虐我们一天了
but they've been killing us with that pass all day.
我的直觉认为他们要传球  但是...
My gut tells me they're gonna pass, but
好吧  让我想想
Okay, just let me think about it.
让开
Move. Move!
那些蠢货
Those dumb bastards
肯定会认为我们要传球  所以我们要奔跑
are going to be thinking pass, which is why we're going to run.
左边用2包围防守
Trap Two, on the left side.
我的副校长对讲机
My vice principal walkie-talkie
不小心收听到了上游河谷教练
accidentally picked up that Upper Valley coach
说出她的白痴娘们战术
calling her dumb lady play.
我要改变我的防守策略吗
Now, was I gonna change my defense?
只有没有骨气  全力争胜  追名逐利的人
Only some spineless win-at-all-costs glory hound
才会选择赢  而不是展示高风亮节
would choose winning over showing some moral fiber.
海豚队赢了  海豚队赢了
Dolphins win! Dolphins win!
感恩节晚餐
体育场里的所有人  包括我
Everybody in that stadium, including me...
-是啊  -都以为对方会传球
- Well... - was expecting a pass.
但你的直觉告诉你不会那样
But your instincts told you something else.
真了不起  我的朋友
That's big-time, my friend.
谢谢你这么说  杰  谢谢你
Well, I-I-I appreciate it, Jay. Uh, thank you.
米奇尔
Mitchell!
我是个骗子
I'm a fraud.
那就别再和那个咖啡师吹牛
Well, then stop telling that barista
说你在百老汇做过沙威[悲惨世界]的替角
that you understudied Javert on Broadway.
他知道你叫什么  上网一查就发现了
He knows your name. He can look it up.
不  我不小心在对讲机上
No, I overheard the lady coach
听到那个女教练的战术安排
call her play on my walkie-talkie,
然后我改了我的防守策略赢了比赛
and I changed my defense to win the game.
现在我焦虑发作  我必须坦白
And now I'm having anxiety, and I have to confess.
不行  你不能坦白
No, you-you are not gonna confess.
你给我把焦虑揉成一个小球
You're gonna smush that anxiety into a little ball,
再塞到你灵魂里那个专门用来
and you're gonna push it into that little, tiny hole
密封童年阴影的小洞里去
in your soul where childhood traumas go.
这里的所有人都是赢家
Everybody here is a winner.
如果最后你成了饭桌上唯一的失败者
I-If you end up being the one loser at the table,
我仅有的收获会是所有人居高临下的同情
I'm gonna get nothing but condescending pity from everybody.
特别是克莱尔那副难以忍受的虚伪嘴脸
Especially Claire, that insufferable phony.
太漂亮了
Hey, so pretty!
-卢克  -歌洛莉亚
- Luke. - Hey, Gloria.
你的刘海真好看
Sure love those bangs.
为什么剪了刘海
What's the story with those?
我知道你一直在躲着我
I know you have been avoiding me
因为根本没有乔身处险境的合成照片
because there are no Photoshopped pictures of Joe in danger.
而你这个问题的答案很简单
And the the answer to your question is very simple --
刘海衬我的脸
They frame my face.
那些照片啊
Oh, those pictures.
就在这
Here we are.
乔捅蜂窝
Joe poking a bees' nest.
肯尼迪遇刺案主凶
乔射杀李·哈维·奥斯瓦尔德
Oh, and Joe killing Lee Harvey Oswald.
真可爱
So cute.
杰  卢克是个天才
Jay, Luke is a genius.
谢了  伙计
Thanks, buddy.
你可以去买高级衣服了
You can go do your fancy shopping now.
太棒了  为了弥补我失去的时间
Awesome. To make up for the time I lost,
我要给脚后跟涂上油
I'm gonna baby oil my heels
试鞋时穿脱就快多了
so I can try on shoes faster.
菲尔  你看过卢克合成的这些照片了吗
Phil, did you see this Photoshop stuff that Luke did?
他真是个魔术师
He's a real magician.
我想这是有其父必有其子
I guess he came by it honestly.
这话对我来说意义非凡  杰
That means the world to me, Jay.
我的人生是场谎言
I'm living a lie.
克莱尔  这家里的每个人都是赢家
Claire, everyone in this family's a winner
除了我
except for me.
我变我变我变废柴
Abraka-failure.
准备好灌水了吗
Ready to fill this thing up?
当天早些时候
我们之所以在这里拍
The-The whole reason we're here
就是为了用泳池水  能重复利用
is to use the pool water, which is recyclable.
我算是可持续魔术运动的大人物
I'm sort of a hero in the sustainable magic movement.
我可不想失去三只环保绿兔的评级
I'd hate to lose my three green rabbits rating.
好吧
Okay.
我们这就开拍吗
Should we start filming?
当然  好  当然
For sure. Yeah. For sure.
我认为我或许该先休息一下
I-I-I think I'll-I'll probably just take a quick minute.
年轻时我表演什么魔术都不害怕
As a young man, I had no fear of any trick
任何被困在狭小空间的魔术都行
where I was jammed into tight spaces --
盒中狐  另一个牧羊人
Fox in a Box, The Wrong Shepherd,
爱因斯坦的鸟浴盆
Einstein's Birdbath.
不过最近  我多少有一点幽闭恐惧
Lately, though, I have had a touch of claustrophobia,
通常我只要
which is usually cleared up
给非常支持我的妻子打通电话就好了
by a quick call to my super-supportive wife.
你终于接电话了
Oh, you finally picked up.
不  没有紧急状况
No, no, it's not an emergency.
我只是...你在听吗  克莱尔
I just -- Hello? Claire?
等着你的指令呢  老爸
Just give me the word, Dad.
好
Yep.
我们
Let's...
-我们开始吧  -好  准备好了吗
- Let's do this. - Great. Ready?
-好了  -开拍
- Yeah. - And...action.
您好  恭喜您购买了这个
Hello, and congratulations on your purchase
诺曼底电话亭
of the Normandy Phone Booth.
接下来我将演示
The following will demonstrate
您为生活"拨动"了多少乐趣
just how much fun you've...dialed up.
今天就是登陆日
Here we are on D-Day.
该死的空中支援在哪
Where's the damned air support?
太好了
Oh, good.
有个电话亭
A p-phone booth.
我听说纳粹们在电话亭里设置了陷阱
I hear the Nazis have booby-trapped these,
但我...
but I will...
我绝对会以身犯险  给盟军司令部打电话
I definitely will take the risk of calling Allied Command.
您好  上将
Hello, General.
是的  我们被敌人包围了
Yes, the enemy is all around us.
火力很猛
Blast!
这个电话亭里设置了陷阱
This is one of the phone booths that's booby-trapped.
不
Oh, no!
是的  上将  敌人正在逼近
Yes, General, the enemy is closing in!
我们无路可逃...
There's no esca-
海莉  快放我出去
Haley! Get me out of here!
海莉是谁  我是卢瑟福护士
Who's Haley? I'm Nurse Rutherford.
如果我不能表演这个魔术
If I can't do this trick,
我的魔术用品店会沦为小型商场的笑柄
my magic shop is gonna be the laughingstock of the mini-mall.
而那里还有一家过时多年的租片店呢
And there's still a Blockbuster there.
亲爱的  我知道你最近过得不顺
Honey, I know you're going through something,
但你不能告诉别人
but you need to keep it to yourself,
因为我们决不能成为今年家里的失败者
because we will not be the loser family this year.
-克莱尔  -怎么
- Claire. - Yeah?
我想到了一个天才点子
I had a genius idea.
你的比赛路线正好经过普利切特衣橱
Your race went right by Pritchett's Closets.
把保全摄像调出来
Pull the security tape.
我们用你领先的画面冲副大广告
We'll blow up a frame of you in the lead and run a big ad --
"普利切特  三十年来一直领先于他人"
"Pritchett's. Leading the Pack for 30 Years."
-天才  -太赞了  老爸  真棒
- Genius! - I love it, Dad! Yes!
我这就去
I am on that!
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
是我有麻烦了
I had a problem.
当天早些时候
你好
H-H-Hello?
你好  该死
Hello -- Damn it.
菲尔  你最好是有紧急状况
Phil, this better be an emergency.
你终于接电话了
Oh, you finally picked up.
不  没有紧急状况  我只是...
No, no, it's not an emergency. I just --
我在赛跑  歌单都因为你乱套了
I'm running a race, and you just screwed up my playlist!
从那一刻起
From that point on,
我就不在赛跑路线上了
I was no longer on the actual race course.
谢谢你
Thank you!
谢谢
Thanks.
后来可能在某个转角我又兜回到比赛路线上
I guess I hit a point where I funneled back onto the course.
我的确注意到我的体能
I did notice that I seemed to have more energy
似乎比我前面的几个人充沛许多
than the few people in front of me,
但我当时没多想
but I didn't-I didn't think much of it.
火鸡跑  终点线
我做到了  我赢了我赢了
I did it! I won! I won!
你看到了吗  宝贝  我赢了
Did you see that, honey? I won!
不  你没赢
Uh, no, you didn't.
我一直站在五千米标志那  根本没看到你
I was standing at the 5K mark and never saw you.
-什么  -克莱尔
- What? - Claire!
我刚才在商店里  我看到你赢了
I was at the store, and I saw you win!
亲爱的
Oh, honey!
我认识她
I know her!
她是我继女
She's my stepdaughter!
普利切特衣橱的保全摄像里
There's not gonna be any footage
根本不会有你跑过去的画面
of you running past Pritchett's Closets
因为9.6公里的赛程你少跑了3公里
because you cut two miles out of a six-mile race.
你最好告诉外公你没赢
Better tell Grandpa you didn't win.
你真是我的道德指南针
Oh, you are my moral compass.
所以我今天一天都不想再和你说话了
Which is why I don't want to talk to you for the rest of the day.
卢克
Luke!
帮我个忙  不许多问
I need a favor, no questions asked.
你需要什么  电话卡吗
What do you need? Phone cards?
不  我需要你合成一张
No. I need you to Photoshop a picture of me from today
我今天跑过普利切特衣橱的照片
running in front of Pritchett's Closets.
没问题
No problem.
-没问题  -我...
- No problem. - I --
我想拍张你和克莱尔的照片
I want to grab a picture of you and Claire.
我想上传到内缝线账号上
I want to post it on my Inseam account.
内缝线是什么
Oh, what's Inseam?
我用来找自制成衣图样的软件
I use it for home tailoring.
-克莱尔  -怎么
- Claire. - Yeah?
你能过来一下吗
Could you get in here, please?
-我的两个超级明星  -好啊
- My two superstars. - Okay!
真不敢相信你膝盖不好还赢了比赛
Can't believe you won with that bad knee.
还好  如果有人想偷奖牌的话
Well, at least if somebody tries to steal that thing,
他们得和这兄弟过过招
they got to get through this guy.
我不过是做了任何英雄会做的事
I just did what any hero would do.
-没什么  -你化妆了吗
- It's... - Are you wearing makeup?
是的  为了遮脸上的淤伤
Uh, well, yeah. I got a bruise.
你不是说你一喊就把他吓跑了吗
I thought-I thought you screamed and he ran away?
我们还是发生了肢体冲突的
Uh, well, there was a-there was a scuffle.
你听从了本能
You went with your instinct.
反抗还是逃跑  你反抗了
Fight or flight. You fought.
我要把这张照片发到内缝线上
I'm gonna post this on Inseam.
双击
Double-click.
该死的
Damn it.
你反抗了
You fought.
You fought?
你跟这个"闯空门的"多近距离接触了
How close did you get to this "intruder"?
克莱尔  你差不多够了
Okay, Claire. That is just about enough.
米奇尔遭受了创伤
Mitchell suffered a trauma,
我不喜欢你这种嘲讽的语气
and I don't appreciate your mocking tone.
容我们失陪  好吗
Excuse us. Okay?
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, sweetie.
我们都能确定两件事
Okay, look, we both know two things for certain --
我穿珊瑚色特好看
I look fabulous in coral,
你根本没打跑过任何闯空门的人
and you didn't fight off any intruder.
这是有背景故事的
There-There is a backstory.
1984年夏天
In the summer of 1984,
在《小子难缠》的影响下
inspired by "The Karate Kid,"
我那阵子特别沉迷于武术
I went through a martial arts phase.
当小卡把那副双节棍拿回家时
When Cam brought those nunchucks home,
我实在是无法抗拒
it was just too much to resist.
你好啊  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
三十年后  又一次到了
30 years later, once again,
使出扫堂腿  技惊四座的时候了
it was time to sweep the leg.
天啊  不
Oh, God. Oh, no!
-你为什么不和我说实话  -我不知道
- Why didn't you just tell me? - I don't know.
你进门就问我是不是有人闯进来了
You-You walked in, and you asked if there was a break-in,
我当时很窘迫  还可能脑震荡了
and I-I was embarrassed and possibly concussed,
所以我就顺水推舟
so I just -- I went with it.
再说不能让我爸和克莱尔知道  明白吗
Besides, my dad and Claire cannot know, okay?
《小子难缠》上映的那年夏天  他们都叫我"功妇"
That whole "Karate Kid" summer, they called me "Kung Sue."
火鸡10分钟后就好了
Turkey is gonna be ready in 10 minutes!
-菲尔在哪  -我会告诉他
- Where is Phil? - I'll let him know.
好
Okay.
-再10分钟  -我做不来
- 10 minutes. - I can't take it!
你就深呼吸  老爸
Just breathe, Dad.
我们要克服你的恐惧
We are breaking this fear of yours.
我要死了
I'm dying here!
看着我
Look at me.
你想要你的余生
Do you want to spend the rest of your life
都只是一名开放空间魔术师吗
as an open-space magician?
这就对了
Yeah.
杰  我在内缝线上看到乔的学校举办了
Jay, I saw on Inseam that there was a Thanksgiving pageant
感恩节大会
at Joe's school.
你为什么没告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我忘了嘛
I totally forgot.
乔一周没上学了
Joe hasn't been in school for a week.
我跟他的老师起了点争执
I had a falling-out with his teacher.
然后被叫去校长办公室
And got sent to the principal's office.
你对巴里什老师说了挺难听的话
You said some pretty harsh things to Mrs. Barrish.
那是因为她在计划的餐会
In my defense, um, this banquet she's planning
不符合史实
is not historically accurate.
比如说  我不记得在首次感恩节餐会上
For example, I don't remember a tandoori chicken option
有印度咖喱鸡啊
at the first Thanksgiving.
我们学校有不同文化种族的孩子
We have children here from many ethnicities,
我们想让大家都有参与感
and we try to make them all feel included.
尽管如此  史书上也没写过餐会时  印第安人
Be that as it may, history does not record Pocahontas
请英国探险家帮忙递生鱼片寿司卷
asking John Smith to pass the sashimi roll
而英国知名军官也在一旁
while Myles Standish helps himself
给自己来点无麸质墨西哥煎蛋
to gluten-free huevos rancheros!
之后火气越来越大  我们被逐出学校
After that, it got heated, and we got expelled.
"我们"吗
"We"?
他们会打来的
But they'll call.
始终需要我的银子
They need my check.
为什么学校什么都没告诉我
Why didn't the school tell me anything?
好像我不在电邮通知名单上了
It's like I am off their e-mail list.
我都没看到过他的变装服
I didn't even see the costumes.
他不用变装啊
Well, he didn't have a costume.
他是解说员  他负责说出整个故事
No, he was the narrator. Kid told the whole story.
宝贝
Ay, papi.
你当时一定超可爱
You must have been so cute.
晚餐的时候给大家表演一次吧
Why don't you perform it for everybody at dinner?
我去拿我的手机  我们得录下来
I'll go get my phone, and we'll film it.
-好吗  -没问题
- Okay? - Yes.
小家伙  我得最快时间帮你补课
I gotta get you up to speed in a hurry, buddy.
感恩节的故事  开始
The story of Thanksgiving. Here goes.
没用
It's no use!
我做不到
I can't do it!
我了个去  她成功了
Sonuvabitch, she did it!
你们看到了吗
See that, people?
又一个超越自己巅峰的人  都感谢我
Another person doing their best, thanks to me.
现在可以开吃了
It's time to eat.
谷歌
Hey, Google,
火鸡还要多久
how much time left on the turkey?
两分钟
Two minutes.
看到没  我能控制那个神经病甜甜圈
See? I can control that crazy doughnut,
也成功达到十万步
I can do the steps.
我做到了两件事
I have two achievements,
而其他人只做到了一件
and the rest have only one.
所以外公真的靠
So, Grandpa really motivated you
说你做不到什么而激励了你是吧
by telling you you couldn't do something, huh?
我要看看这个计步器  我写报告要用
I need to see that My StepCounter for a paper I'm writing.
大家都成功做到了一些事
Everybody achieved something today,
现在轮到乔了
so now it's Joe's turn.
乔
Joe...
跟我们说说第一个感恩节的故事
tell us about the first Thanksgiving.
来吧  小家伙
Come up here, buddy.
你能行
You got this.
曾有一片大地住着不信神的原住民
There was once a land of godless natives.
他们愚蠢无知
They did not know any better
直到某天  白人们来了
until, one day, the white man arrived.
这是什么鬼
What is this?
白人们可怜这些原始人
The white man took pity on these primitives
教导他们如何耕种土地
by teaching them to cultivate the land.
但他们的善良被误会为侵略
But their kindness was mistaken for aggression,
所以战争开打了
and a war began.
这是哪门子的鬼学校
What kind of school is this?
-我小时候学到的也是这样  -什么
- This is what I was taught. - What?
最后  一切回归和平
Eventually, peace was restored,
我们还送给了他们我国最高荣誉
and we bestowed them with our nation's highest honor --
让他们冠名橄榄球队
naming football teams for them.
乔  这是什么短剧
Joe, what play is this?
我没有演出短剧  我都没上学了
I wasn't in a play! I don't go to school anymore!
好啦  对啦
All right, fine.
我们被踢出来了可以吗
We got kicked out, okay?
跟校长小小吵了一架
Little argument with the principal.
你怎么可以骗我
You've been lying to me
亏我还一直夸你是个超棒的父亲
while I was celebrating you as an amazing father?
歌洛莉亚  奇怪了
Hey, Gloria, this is weird.
我下载了你的计步器数据
You know, I downloaded your My StepCounter data
到我电脑里
onto my computer,
数据显示你今早走的路线
and it's showing your path this morning
跟我妈妈去赛跑的路线是一样的
was the same route my mom took in her race.
我怎么可能跑得到十万步
I was never going to get 100,000 steps.
一直到后来我知道克莱尔要去火鸡赛跑
But then I learned that Claire was going on a Turkey Trot.
第二次我抱她时
The second time I hugged her,
比第一次不容易  因为她浑身是汗
it was a little harder because she was really wet.
所以我基本上就是你的计步代跑骡吗
So I'm basically just your StepCounter mule?
我还以为你在乎我这场跑步呢
I thought you cared about my race.
我很爱你  克莱尔
I love you very much, Claire,
但我对你运动真的很没兴趣
but your exercise doesn't really interest me.
等等  克莱尔什么时候经过公司的来着
Hang on. When did Claire run past Pritchett's Closets?
因为上面显示她压根就没靠近过那里
'Cause this thing says she never got near it.
爸  估计是计步器出错了
Well, it's probably the StepCounter made a mistake.
是吗  还是...
Oh, yeah, did it? Or -- Or --
还是你绕捷径了
Or did you take a little shortcut?
才没有  应该是我跑太快
No, I was probably going so fast
它都跟不上我的脚步
it couldn't even keep up with me.
-我有照片为证  -让我看...
- I have a picture of it. - Let me see.
卢克
Luke?
你们看
And there you go.
很清楚能看到我跑过普里契特衣柜公司
That is me clearly running in front of Pritchett's Closets.
对啊  窗上还有
Oh, yeah, yeah. With a Reagan/Bush poster
84年总统大选的海报呢
in the window, huh?
照片是假的
The photo is a fake.
不能怪我  是曼尼改的图
It's not my fault. Manny made it.
曼尼改了所有的图吗
Manny was photoshopping everything?
所以乔真的发生危险了吗
So Joe was in real danger?
我没想到你这么轻易
I did not realize how easy it would be
就能把线索都连上
for you to connect those dots.
对你挺失望的  卢克
Pretty disappointed in you, Luke.
他从哪学坏的  我想大家都懂
Well, you know, it's easy to see where he learned it from.
他老妈就是个骗子
His mother's a cheater!
什么  你少跟我搞这套义愤填膺的了
What?! Oh, don't get so hot and bothered. Uh-huh! Mm.
-你的妆都要花了  你这...  -别碰我
- Your makeup's already running, and what do... - Stop it.
你的淤青上有个中文字吗
Do you have a Chinese character on your bruise?
估计是闯入的人打我时  他戒指的字印的
Yeah, it's probably an imprint from the intruder's ring.
他...  我确定他肯定是混什么帮派之类的
He was -- I'm sure he was in a gang of some sort.
老实交代吧  米奇尔
Just give it up, Mitchell.
他玩我以代理副校长职权
He knocked himself out with some nunchucks
没收的双节棍时不小心打到了自己
that I confiscated as acting vice principal.
天啊  功妇又回来了
Oh, my God! Kung Sue is back.
老爸  你听到了吗
Daddy, did you hear that?
小卡  小卡不是靠实力赢的球赛
Well, Cam -- Cam didn't really win the football game.
他从对方女教练那里偷听人家战术
Uh-huh. He stole the last play from the lady coach!
是意外  我不小心在我做为代理副校长
Accidentally! I overheard it on a walkie-talkie
必需要有的对讲机里听到的
that I require as an acting vice principal,
我对这职位感到十分骄傲
which is a position I'm pretty proud of
因为我基本就是个警长
because I'm basically a sheriff.
-你才不...  -就是  我基本就是警长
- You're not basically -- No. Yes, I am basically a sheriff!
我戴着帽子
I wear a hat!
爸要表演那个魔术了  他从来没做过呢
Dad is doing his trick, and he's never done it before.
有可能会死
He could die.
快来
Come on!
菲尔  亲爱的  别啊
Oh, Phil. Honey, wait!
-你不用做这个的  -我必须要做
- You don't have to do this. - Yes, I do!
我是一大家人生赢家里的唯一废柴
I'm the only loser in a remarkable family of winners.
不不  不是的
No, no, no!
我们才不是什么赢家
We are not all winners!
其实我们全都是废柴
It turned out we all stink!
无所谓了
It doesn't matter!
不想要被恐惧支配我的人生
I don't want to live a life ruled by fear!
我今天就得表演这个魔术
I have to do this trick today.
不过有点越来越难呼吸了
Although, it is getting hard to breathe!
别停  老爸  你可以的
Don't stop, Dad! You can do this!
我对你有信心
I believe in you!
-这话说了没用啊  宝贝  -有意思
- That's not helping, honey! - Very interesting.
我一鼓作气做完吧
Okay, I'm just gonna try to barrel through this.
这里是诺曼底  我是美国大兵托尼·兰切提
It's Normandy. I'm an American G.I. Named Tony Ranzetti.
我来自布鲁克林  我最爱我妈做的家常菜
I'm from Brooklyn, and I love my mama's home cooking!
但我觉得我逃不出来了
But I don't think I'm gonna be able to get out!
是托尼的台词  还是菲尔真逃不出
Is he talking as Tony Ranzetti or as Phil?
你们这些孬种有病啊
What is wrong with you cowards?!
菲尔需要帮忙
Phil needs help!
功妇再次出击
Kung Sue's back at it.
来不及逃啦
It's too late to get out! Oh.
-不要啊  -这就是个错误
-No! -This was a mistake!!
好像真的不对  老爸
Something's wrong. Dad?
天啊  菲尔  菲尔
Oh, God. Phil! Phil!
-天啊  -什  什么...
- Oh, my God! -What -- What...
哇靠  他上哪去了
Holy crap, where'd he go?!
兰切提二等兵报告  天神作战成功
Private Ranzetti reporting Operation Overlord is a success.
鸡尾酒我请
Cocktails are on me.
太厉害了  谁都不服就服你  菲尔
That was amazing! Gotta hand it to you, Phil.
火鸡的大鸡腿给你吃
You get the big turkey leg.
派对重新回到桌上
Let's take this party to the table!
不赞吗  嬉皮士们
Come on, hippies.
小卡  很晚了
Cam. It's late.
小卡  我明天得早起干活
Cam, I have work early in the morning.
卡梅隆  你这样我没法睡
Cameron! I cannot sleep!
那你下次应该先考虑清楚
Well, you should have thought about that
再挑衅我  发出我无法在一天内
before you challenged me that I couldn't do
跑完十万步的挑战啊
100,000 steps in a day.
你还差多少
Well, how close are you?
125步
125.
好吧  行
Okay, fine.
等等  是剩125步吧
Wait. 125 left?
不是
Nope.
天啊
Oh, my God.